Guide to the Clark E. Warburton papers, 1920-1979
George Mason University Libraries
- Clark Warburton Papers
  - Annual Report for 1934- Charts and tables, memoranda and correspondence. (Folder 1, 2, Box 111)
  - Annual Report for 1935- Organization chart. (Folder 3, 4, Box 111)
  - Annual Report for 1937- Preliminary Drafts of Part I and Part II, correspondence. (Folder 5-7, Box 111)
  - Annual Report for 1938- Computation of Part IV tables, examination analysis, preliminary tables, committee on style, texts and tables, earnings, preliminary drafts of Part I, II, III, and proposals for deposit guaranty legislation. (Folder 8-17, Box 111)
  - FDIC- Balance sheet together with auditors' certificate. (Folder 18, Box 111)
  - Annual Report for 1939- Examination analysis preliminary tables, texts and tables, committee on style, earnings, preliminary drafts of Part I, II, and V, and material from other divisions. (Folder 19-27, Box 111)
  - Annual Report for 1956- Parts 1a, 1b, and 2. (Folder 28-30, Box 111)
  - Annual Report for 1957- Parts 2, 3, 4, and 5. (Folder 31-34, Box 111)
  - Miscellaneous (Folder 35, Box 111)
  - State Banking Authorities- Identical letters, Alaska, Alabama, Delaware, Florida, Louisiana, Hawaii. (Folder 1-5, Box 112)
  - State Banking Authorities- Supervision of the State Bank of Indiana 1834-1857. (Folder 6, Box 112)
  - State Banking Authority- Maine, Missouri, Montana, Ohio, Oklahoma, Oregon, Pennsylvania, Puerto Rico, Rhode Island, Wyoming, Virgin Islands. (Folder 7-14, Box 112)
  - State Studies- Deposit Guaranty in Kansas, Nebraska and, Oklahoma by Clark Warburton. (Folder 15-17, Box 112)
  - Extracts from the Correspondence of the Board of Control, State Bank of Ohio 1848-1864. (Folder 18, Box 112)
  - Stockholders, Double Liability. (Folder 19, Box 112)
  - Miscellaneous- Correspondence (1) (Folder 20, Box 112)
  - Manuscript by Clark Warburton on Deposit Guaranty. (Folder 21, Box 112)
  - Miscellaneous items- not correspondence. (Folder 22, Box 112)
  - Miscellaneous- Correspondence (2) (Folder 23, Box 112)
  - Studies- Relation of banking to business fluctuations, bank assets and liabilities in the early 19th century. (Folder 1, Box 113)
  - Supervisors of State Banks. (Folder 2, Box 113)
  - Summary of Deposits 1966. (Folder 3, Box 113)
  - Suspensions- FRS 1931-1933. (Folder 4, 5, Box 113)
  - Trade Associations- Banking Journal, Moody's Investor Service. (Folder 6, 7, Box 113)
  - Top Secret. (Folder 8, Box 113)
  - Department of Treasury. (Folder 9, Box 113)
  - Trust powers. (Folder 10, Box 113)
  - Uniform report of condition. (Folder 11, Box 113)
  - U.S. government securities owned by FDIC. (Folder 12, Box 113)
  - Westerfield and White Paper- "Principles of Banking Reform." (Folder 13, Box 113)
  - White House. (Folder 14, Box 113)
  - Proposal to insure deposits of foreign banking institutions in the U.S. (Folder 15, Box 113)
  - Foreign banks operating in the U.S.- Memoranda, correspondence, etc. Foreign banks in New York and California. (Folder 16-19, Box 113)
  - Authority and responsibilities of supervising agencies. (Folder 20, Box 113)
  - Blanket Fidelity Coverage held by insured banks not members of the FRS during the 1964 examination. (Folder 21, Box 113)
  - Data processing operations. (Folder 22, Box 113)
  - Arthur D. Little Inc. (Folder 23, Box 113)
  - Sperry Rand- Correspondence and data processing. (Folder 24, Box 113)
  - Purchasing (Folder 25, Box 113)
  - Memoranda prepared by Clark Warburton, 1934-1965. (Folder 1, Box 114)
  - Memoranda to files from Mr. Golembe. (Folder 2, Box 114)
  - Insurance of bank obligations in six states during the period 1829-1866, by Charles H. Golembe and Clark Warburton 1958 (Copy # 1, 2, 3). (Folder 3-5, Box 114)
  - Regulation of interest rate, 1934. (Folder 6, Box 114)
  - Submitted article- Forces Producing Disturbances in the Value of Output, 1960. Lecture- Monetary Disturbances and Business Fluctuations by Clark Warburton. (Folder 7, Box 114)
  - Work on progress- 1940, 1945. (Folder 8, Box 114)
  - Correspondence index, August 1951- January 1953. (Folder 9, Box 114)
  - Deposit insurance assessment of FDIC, 1950-1970. (Folder 1, Box 115)
  - Selection of Bank Loans for Evaluation and Cash Budgeting by Yair E. Orgler. (Folder 2, 3, Box 115)
  - Miscellaneous, memoranda, etc. (Folder 4, Box 115)
  - Two pamphlets by FDIC. (Folder 5, Box 115)
  - Miscellaneous, 1968-1969. (Folder 6, Box 115)
  - Recent library acquisitions, 1969. (Folder 7, Box 115)
  - Two research reports by Yair E. Orgler. (Folder 8, Box 115)
  - "Estimating Potential Losses From Public Bank Installment Loans: A Markow Chains Approach" by Yair E. Orgler. (Folder 9, Box 115)
  - Correspondence, 1969. (Folder 10, Box 115)
  - Losses in closed commercial banks, 1921-1933. (Folder 1, Box 116)
  - Number of deposits, loans, and investments of commercial banks December 31, 1935. (Folder 2, Box 116)
  - Banks- Merged, closed, etc. 1944-1966. (Folder 3, Box 116)
  - Memoranda- Mr. Hengren, Mr. Warburton, 1968-1968, 1970. (Folder 4, 8, 11, Box 116)
  - Two research papers by Yair Orgler, 1968. (Folder 6, Box 116)
  - Correspondence, 1968-1969. (Folder 7, Box 116)
  - Loan classification regulation results. (Folder 9, Box 116)
  - Report to insured banks 1958. (Folder 10, Box 116)
  - "Sources of Bank Capital and Trends in Capital Ratios Since 1870" by Robert Moss- Preliminary draft 1962. (Folder 1, Box 117)
  - Summary of assets and liabilities of all banks in the U.S. and other areas, December 31, 1965. (Folder 2, Box 117)
  - Financial Report of State Chartered Banks Registered Under SEA of 1934-1965. (Folder 3, Box 117)
  - Proposed answers to questions addressed to the FDIC by the Joint Committee on the Economic Report August, 1949. (Folder 4, Box 117)
  - State member bank call reports- December call 1959-1962. (Folder 5, Box 117)
  - Summary tables and miscellaneous on problem banks 1959-1965. (Folder 6, Box 117)
  - Problem banks- National, state members, non-members 1959-1965. (Folder 7-9, Box 117)
  - Recapitulation- Problem banks 1959-1965. (Folder 10, Box 117)
  - Serious problem banks. 12-31-65 (Folder 11, Box 117)
  - Problem national banks(Call Reports) 1959-1962. (Folder 12, Box 117)
  - Outline for filing procedure. (Folder 13, Box 117)
  - List of file contents. (Folder 14, Box 117)
  - File notes in FDIC file reorganization 1963-1964. (Folder 15, Box 117)
  - Some observations on banking services from the point of view of convenience and needs of the community. 8-24-45 (Folder 16, Box 117)
  - Economic aspects of exchange changes and par clearance. 4-12-44 (Folder 17, Box 117)
  - Eleven years of research at the FDIC. 11-20-45 (Folder 18, Box 117)
  - Insurance of bank obligations in six states during the period 1829-1866 by Carter H. Golembe and Clark Warburton. (Folder 19a, 19b, Box 117)
  - The work of the FDIC- 1950. (Folder 20, Box 117)
  - The purpose of insurance of accounts in savings institutions. (Folder 21, Box 117)
  - What is the FDIC? (Folder 22, Box 117)
  - Two questions pertaining to the FDIC. 9-5-40 (Folder 23, Box 117)
  - Consolidated report of income- Monthly. 9-30-80 (Folder 24, Box 117)
  - Unidentified loose page. (Folder 25, Box 117)
  - Purpose and problems of deposit insurance. (Folder 26, Box 117)
  - Memorandum to Florence Helm- Insurance coverage, financial status of the FDIC. (Folder 27, 28, Box 117)
  - Financial Structure of the Division of Research and Statistics. 3-27-46 (Folder 29, Box 117)
  - Memorandum- Needed deposit insurance fund in the event of a wave of bank failures accompanying a deep and prolonged recession, regulation of the maximum interest rate payable on deposit. 8-16-55, 5-11-56 (Folder 30-32, Box 117)
  - Proposed statement regarding the deposit insurance assessment rate and size of the Deposit Insurance Fund. 9-15-55 (Folder 33, Box 117)
  - Investment of the Deposit Insurance Fund: Reconsideration of asset management policies. 2-12-58 (Folder 34, Box 117)
  - Memorandum- Purpose of deposit insurance and the appropriate limit to insurance coverage, the monetary purpose of deposit insurance. (Folder 35, 36, Box 117)
  - Annual report for 1953- Part I. 1-14-54 (Folder 37, Box 117)
  - Annual report for 1954- Part I. 2-11-55 (Folder 38, Box 117)
  - Prohibition of interest on demand deposits. 4-28-64, 7-9-62 (Folder 39, 43, Box 117)
  - Variation of deposit insurance assessments according to risk ratios. 7-13-62 (Folder 40, Box 117)
  - Broadening of Federal Insurance Coverage for Deposits and Shares. 7-13-62 (Folder 41, Box 117)
  - Federal chartering and insurance for savings banks. 7-11-62 (Folder 42, Box 117)
  - The purpose of deposit insurance. 6-25-62 (Folder 44, Box 117)
  - The purpose of insurance accounts in savings institutions. 6-25-62 (Folder 45, Box 117)
  - Regulation of the maximum interest rate payable on deposits. 3-1-62 (Folder 46, Box 117)
  - Memorandum- Bank borrowing. 6-25-38 (Folder 47, Box 117)
  - Memorandum- Extension of insurance coverage to all direct liabilities. 8-4-38 (Folder 48, Box 117)
  - Memorandum to Mr. Fox- Duties of the Division of Research and Statistics, effective bank supervision under the proposed deposit insurance act. (Folder 49, 50, Box 117)
  - "A Hedge Against Inflation" by Clark Warburton. 12-20-50 (Folder 51, Box 117)
  - "The Work of the FDIC" by Edison H. Cramer. 4-7-50 (Folder 52, Box 117)
  - Answers to questions of the Subcommittee on General Credit Control and Debt Management. 11-30-51 (Folder 53, Box 117)
  - Memorandum- Questionnaire of the Joint Committee on the Economic Report. 9-30-49 (Folder 54, Box 117)